FARNOOD FOROUDI

PRODUCT DESIGNER

farnood.me foroudi@gmail.com (+372) 5367 1295

Skills

Design

Illustration and UI graphics Strategy and vision presentations

User flows

Concept sketches

Wireframes and mock ups

Motion design

Design systems principles

Style guides and pattern libraries

Design Ops

Localisation and RTL Support

Prototype

Rapid prototyping Interactive flows

Interactions and transitions

HTML/CSS/JS prototyping

Research

Interviewing

Usability testing

A/B Testing

Statistical analysis

Tools

Sketch

Figma

Adobe Creative Suite

Principle App

Flinto

Origami

Zeplin Abstract

Zeroheiaht

InVision

Mixpanel

Taplytics

Tableau

Google Analytics / Firebase

MindNode

Aha!

Jira and Confluence

Ping Pong

Education

BS Software Engineering Shomal University, Amol, Iran 2005-2011

About

I'm a product designer from Iran, now living in Tallinn, Estonia. I have 8 years experience designing and crafting digital products. I've been working in multiple popular Iranian and international products, defining their product strategy, design approach and solutions for the users. I have a solid background in interface design, user experience and interactiomn design.

Work Experience

Monese / Product Designer - Onboarding Experience

AUG 2019 - PRESENT, TALLINN, ESTONIA

As the product designer in the Onboarding team, I work on Monese Onboarding and KYC experience to be more convenient for the users, while aligning with the regulations and security measures. My commitment is to find the best solutions based on data from user tests, quant data, researches, and A/B testings. I also helped to build the Monese accessibility team, focused on bringing accessibility features to our apps. I'm currently working with the different stakeholders directly to completely re-design the onboarding flow during multiple design sprints.

Alibaba Travels / Product Manager - Mobile Applications

FEB 2019 - AUG 2019, TEHRAN, IRAN

• I've built a product development process to manage the complete existing app redesign with multi-language support alongside the expanding of product coverage and development of new mobile-only features with speed and future scalability in mind • I was directly working with 2 UX designer in my team to deliver a brand new design, based on user researches, usability testing • I worked with the marketing team to utilize the marketing automation tool inside the apps • I helped the company to recruit, shape and build the product design team to form a chapter of product designers • I initiated the Alibaba's Design Language System by building it for the mobile apps. Alibaba is the biggest OTA in Iran and has more than 15M users.

Kian Capital Management / Product Designer - Personal Banking and Onboarding

FEB 2018 - FEB 2019, TEHRAN, IRAN

My main responsibility was to create and shape a new digital banking/personal finance management experience in Iran • I was responsible for taking the digital banking from ideation to production. This included vision setting, conducting research, designing solutions, creating high-fidelity visuals, prototyping new ideas, presenting work to our cross-functional teams, and overseeing implementation • I designed a complex KYC and On-Boarding process to tackle the problems of bank account opening procedure in Iran • I successfully designed a robust design structure for Kian's future product expansion • I initiated and led the first version of Kian Design Language System in collaboration with other product designers in my team.

Dunro / Product Designer

SEP 2015 - FEB 2018, TEHRAN, IRAN

During my time at Dunro, I crafted and developed the product's vision to evolve iBartar (former name of Dunro) from a local business search engine to a complete location-based city guide application with social contribution and network platform • I was in charge of ideation and production of core business values like Targeted Advertisement Platform, Rate and Review System, Dunro's Gamification Platform, new Adding Locations Flow, Social Feed and the Superusers Program • The DAU and user retention rates successfully increased by more than 40% in 6 months after introducing our social and gamification features • Our app users boosted from 100K to 500K in 1 year. We managed to raise a \$15M investment that year by Aftab Group • During my time, Dunro won the Iran Web and Mobile Awards, twice, for being the best application in Travel and Lifestyle segments.

Seeb Mobile Technologies / Co-Founder, UI-UX Designer

OCT 2013 - MAY 2015, TEHRAN, IRAN

I founded Seeb as a mobile solutions agency to offer mobile application development, consultancy and product design to Iranian companies • We successfully designed and developed mobile apps by contract for great companies in Iran like NetBarg (Coupon Deals), Parsian Bank (Mobile Bank App), Buyex (Online Apparel Shop), Fidilio (Popular Restaurant Review App) • We also launched a series of applications for our company like Tehran Air (Air Quality Check), SeebStore (A payment solution for Iranian users with no access to visa/master), Golabi (An iOS trivia game) • I was a multidisciplinary individual working mainly on product design and project management.

Mapna Group / UI-UX Designer

OCT 2012 - SEP 2014, TEHRAN, IRAN

I started off my professional career with Mapna Group, working on internal enterprise portals over Microsoft SharePoint foundation. During my time at Mapna I successfully turned the majority of traditional paperwork workflows into fully automated workflows in collaboration with the Systems and Quality department engineers. I was also in charge of designing and developing the company's website which I successfully designed and developed and launched it on .NET platform.